Department of Education Records UA071
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Qualifying papers, 2007 -- 2014; UA071.001; 26 Digital Object(s)
  - Children's materials science practices before, during, and after a design-based science learning experience, 2009; UA071.001.001.00025; Wendell, Kristen B.
    A qualifying paper submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy in Math, Science, Technology, and Engineering Education. Abstract: Materials science, which entails the practices of selecting, testing, and characterizing materials, is an important discipline within the study of matter. This paper examines how third grade students' materials science performance changes over the course of instruction based on an engineering design challenge. I conducted a case study of nine students who participated in engineering design-based science instruction with the goal of constructing a stable, quiet, thermally comfortable model house. The learning outcome of materials science practices was assessed by clinical interviews conducted before and after the instruction, and the learning process was assessed by students' workbooks completed during the instruction. The interviews included two materials selection tasks for designing a sturdy stepstool and an insulated pet habitat. Results indicate that (1) students significantly improved on both materials selection tasks, (2) their gains were significantly positively associated with the degree of completion of their workbooks, and (3) students who were highly engaged with the workbook's reflective record-keeping tasks showed the greatest improvement on the interviews. These findings suggest the important role workbooks can play in facilitating elementary students' learning of science through authentic activity such as engineering design.
    Teaching - methods; Science - Study and teaching; Education, Elementary; Dept. of Education
  - A ten-year-old child's representations of motion, 2012; UA071.001.001.00026; Kendall, Amber; This paper presents the case study of a 10-year-old boy and the various representations he produces to express his ideas about the motion of a car through three clinical interviews. This work also provides an initial exploration of using animation (SAM Animation software, http://www.samanimation.com) as an alternative to conventional graphing in the elementary classroom, to quantitatively represent understandings of motion in a form closer to children's spontaneous figurative drawing. The goals of this study were to explore the invented representations of motion produced by a 10 year old boy; how his paper and pencil representations compared to those produced through animations; and how his understandings of time, displacement, speed, and acceleration were expressed through the representations he created. Two types of drawings (figurative and non-figurative) and one animation of the motion of a car produced by an elementary student were examined to compare the resources used in their creation and the ways in which they allowed me to explore the students' understandings of motion. Many resources previously observed in other students' works, such as drawings, words, "more is more," temporal sequences, and line segments were present in all three types of representation. The figurative drawings exhibited rudimentary understandings of motion, representing changes in the car's speed as snapshots rather than continuous accelerations. The non-figurative representations depicted slightly more quantitative information about speed and acceleration using almost the same set of resources, but incorporating the idea of acceleration as changing speed. The child recognized the potential for demonstrating "real life" motion within the medium of animation, but his actual product shared more similarities with the resources of the static figurative drawings that he had produced than his non-figurative representations, in which he represented quantities more explicitly. However, the animation's explicit treatment of time, and small ___t, provided the basis for the exploration of the "A x B = C" relationships between speed, displacement, and duration, and speed, acceleration and duration. The three forms of representation provided for varied contexts through which his understandings of speed, time, and acceleration articulated in the drawings could be explored in the resulting discussions about his productions.
  - What Is Speed: A Young Chinese Adult Non-Scientist's Epistemologies and Her Understandings of Speed, 2012; UA071.001.001.00027; Cao, Ying; In science education studies, researchers have thoroughly investigated the epistemologies held by students who are learning science. These research findings, however, have yet to be applied to individuals who are not currently enrolled in science classes. Additionally, these studies have primarily focused on individuals from Western cultures and who are native English speakers. In this paper I examine an individual to see whether the research claims in relation to students' epistemologies still apply to someone with different characteristics. Overall, I aimed to investigate whether Hammer and colleagues' claims concerning learners' epistemologies (e.g., Hammer, 1994; Hammer, Elby, Scherr, & Redish, 2005) can be more widely applied than their previous research has indicated by extending these claims to individuals who lack advanced science training, have had different learning experiences, and who grew up speaking and learning in another language and culture. The findings show that previous theoretical frameworks can be used to explain the epistemologies of the individual examined in this study. The case suggests that these theories may apply to individuals regardless of the learner's science background, language, education experience, and cultural background. More cases should be examined with learners with different academic backgrounds and from different cultures if we want to provide more compelling evidence for this claim.
  - Affect and the scientific pursuit: Learning to feel like a scientist, 2013-07-23; UA071.001.001.00028; Jaber, Lama Ziad; This paper argues that affect is central to scientific pursuits and to engaging in science conceptually and epistemologically. To ground this claim, we first review accounts of scientists' intellectual practices that suggest that science involves the activation and refinement of affective resources, such as excitement for figuring things out, annoyance at inconsistencies, empathy with the object of inquiry, and persistence in the face of challenges. We then discuss a case study from a fourth grade science classroom which shows that (1) science learners can experience disciplinary feelings and emotions similar to those of scientists; (2) these affective experiences are closely entwined with the conceptual and epistemological substance of student engagement; and (3) they are consequential to the nature and flow of inquiry. Affect, we contend, is part and parcel of scientific pursuits, and learning science is in part learning how to feel like a scientist. We conclude with some implications of this perspective on research and instruction.
    A qualifying paper submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy In Science Education.
  - Attending to Affect in Student Inquiry, 2014; UA071.001.001.00029; Jaber, Lama Z.; This paper explores dynamics of attending and responding to affect as integral to, rather than separate from, attending to the substance of students" ideas. I examine the relationship between responsiveness to affect and the disciplinary substance of student thinking. The questions I consider are: how does a teacher attend and respond to affect as integral to the substance of student reasoning and ideas in the science class? And how do these acts of attending and responding become consequential to student engagement? Using a case study of a fifth grade teacher's interactions with a student struggling to communicate an idea, I illustrate how the teacher's attention and responsiveness to affect was an act of attending to the student's reasoning and persistence. Moreover, I show how intending for his student to struggle at the intellectual level was an act of caring for him as an intellectual agent. In this way, I show how caring can be connected to and in service of student disciplinary engagement and epistemic agency. More broadly, I highlight the need to examine affect as inherent to the discipline in conversations on responsive teaching and I discuss implications on instruction and teacher education.
    A qualifying paper submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy in Education.
    Department of Education records.; Teachers--Psychology.; Teacher-student relationships.; Teachers--Attitudes.; Affect (Psychology)
  - Attention to Student Framing in Responsive Teaching, 2014; UA071.001.001.00030; Radoff, Jennifer A.; A central issue of responsive teaching involves how teachers decide, tacitly or explicitly, to distribute their attention in the classroom. Even within the narrow realm of attending and responding to the substance of student thinking, teachers must constantly make decisions about what student thinking to pursue and how to pursue it. In this paper, we explore a third-grade teacher's shift in the scope of her attention, from a wider consideration of the class's sense of what they are doing"their epistemological framing"to a more narrow consideration of the conceptual substance of particular ideas. We claim that a key factor influencing the teacher's scoping of attention is her sense of the stability of students" framing.
    A qualifying paper submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Doctor of Philosophy in Education
    Department of Education records.; Teachers--Psychology.; Teacher-student relationships.; Teachers--Attitudes.
  - High School Students' Understandings and Representations of the Electric Field, 2014; UA071.001.001.00031; Cao, Ying; This study investigates the understandings and representations of the electric field expressed by Chinese high school students ages 15 to 16 who have not yet received high school-level physics instruction. The literature has reported students' ideas of the electric field post-instruction as indicated by their performance on textbook-style questionnaires. However, by relying on measures such as questionnaires, previous research has inadequately captured the thinking process that led students to answer questions in the ways that they did. The present study portrays the beginning of this process by closely examining students' understandings pre-instruction. The participants in this study were asked to engage in a lesson that included informal group tasks that involved playing a Web-based hockey game that replicated an electric field and drawing comic strips that used charges as characters. The lesson was videotaped, students' work was collected, and three students were interviewed afterward to ascertain more detail about their work. I identified nine ideas related to the electric field that students spontaneously leveraged, even though they had yet to receive formal instruction on the topic. In this paper, I will discuss my findings in comparison with previous research claims.
    Department of Education records.; Tufts University. Department of Education; Electric fields--Study and teaching (Secondary)
- Additional accessions, UA071.002
  - Liberal Arts Education box, UA071.002.002 (Box data_value_missing_ce64662cf04bbc2baabf3e112b542184, Box 2)
- 2017 accessions, 1954; UA071.003; .1 Linear Feet
  This series is open for research.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Lawrence Rudd, 2017, accession UA-2018-027.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains one slide box of color slides taken by Lonie Rudd at an outdoor education camp for Tufts School of Education students in 1954. The slides may have been taken by or belonged to Bradley Palmer, who taught math education.
  Custodial History
  These slides were gifted by Lawrence Rudd to the Tufts University Office of Alumni Relations in November 2017. This office donated the slides to DCA in December 2017.
  - Outdoor education camp slides, 1954; UA071.003.002.00001; .1 Linear Feet (Box data_value_missing_ce64662cf04bbc2baabf3e112b542184, Box 2)